[
    {
        "front": "vector",
        "back": "An ordered collection of numbers that has an accompanying set of mathematical operations."
    },
    {
        "front": "order",
        "back": "The number of axes used to index the contents of a  mathematical object, such as a vector, matrix,  or tensor."
    },
    {
        "front": "scalar",
        "back": "A single numerical value."
    },
    {
        "front": "component (vector) <br> or <br> element (vector)",
        "back": "One of the numerical values that make up the vector."
    },
    {
        "front": "size (vector) <br> or <br> dimension (vector)",
        "back": "The number of components a vector contains."
    },
    {
        "front": "quiver plot",
        "back": "A (two-dimensional) plot that illustrates one or more  vectors as arrows that are typically specified by a location, which determines  the coordinates of the tail of the vector, and some specification of the  direction and magnitude of the vector. If no location is provided, then the  origin $(0,0)$ is used."
    },
    {
        "front": "tail (vector)",
        "back": "The starting point of a vector (the initial\npoint from which the displacement is measured)."
    },
    {
        "front": "head (vector)",
        "back": "The ending point of a vector (the point  at which the vector terminates after the specified displacement from the tail)."
    },
    {
        "front": "scatter plot",
        "back": "A (two-dimensional) scatter plot takes a sequence of two-dimensional data points $(x_0, y_0)$, $(x_1, y_1)$, $\\ldots$, $(x_{n-1}, y_{n-1})$ and plots symbols (called <I>markers</I>) that represent the locations of the points in a rectangular region of a plane."
    },
    {
        "front": "time-series data",
        "back": "Data that is collected over time, usually at regular intervals. Each data point is associated with a timestamp indicating when the data was collected."
    },
    {
        "front": "bar chart <br> or <br> bar graph",
        "back": "Most commonly used with categorical data for which each category has an associated quantity or measurement, a bar is drawn for each category, where the height or width of the bar is proportional to the associated quantity or measurement."
    },
    {
        "front": "zero vector",
        "back": "A vector of all zeros.<br> <b>Ex:</b> $\\mathbf{0} = \\begin{bmatrix} 0 & 0 & 0 \\end{bmatrix}^T$"
    },
    {
        "front": "ones vector",
        "back": "A vector of all ones.<br> <b>Ex:</b> $\\mathbf{1} = \\begin{bmatrix} 1 & 1 & 1 \\end{bmatrix}^T$"
    },
    {
        "front": "standard unit vector",
        "back": "A vector with all of its components equal to zero, except one element that is equal to one.<br> <b>Ex: </b>$\\mathbf{e}_1 = \\begin{bmatrix} 1 & 0 & 0 \\end{bmatrix}^T$"
    },
    {
        "front": "addition (vectors)",
        "back": "The sum of $n$ vectors \\(\\mathbf{a}\\) and   \\(\\mathbf{b}\\) is a vector \\(\\mathbf{a+b}\\) such that any component $i$ of the   vector sum is the sum of the \\(i\\)th components of \\(\\mathbf{a}\\) and   \\(\\mathbf{b}\\); i.e. \\(\\mathbf{(a+b)}_i = a_i + b_i,~~i=0, 1,\\ldots, n-1\\)."
    },
    {
        "front": "multiplication (scalar-vector)",
        "back": "Given a vector \\(\\mathbf{u}\\) and a scalar \\(\\alpha\\), define \\(\\alpha \\mathbf{u}\\) such that each component \\(i\\) of \\(\\alpha \\mathbf{u}\\) is given by \\((\\alpha \\mathbf{u})_i = \\alpha u_i\\). "
    },
    {
        "front": "broadcasting (NumPy)",
        "back": "In NumPy, broadcasting occurs in operations involving two arrays of different shapes. The smaller array is <I>broadcast</I> across the larger array by repeating values in the smaller array in such a way that the shapes of the two arrays will match."
    },
    {
        "front": "component-wise multiplication (vectors) <br> or <br> Hadamard product (vectors) <br> or <br> Schur product (vectors)",
        "back": "Given \\(n\\)-vectors \\(\\mathbf{u}\\) and \\(\\mathbf{v}\\), the <I>Hadamard product</I> or <I>Schur product</I> is denoted \\(\\mathbf{u} \\odot \\mathbf{v}\\) and is the \\(n\\)-vector given by component-wise multiplication of \\(\\mathbf{u}\\) and \\(\\mathbf{v}\\), \\begin{equation*}  \\mathbf{u} \\odot \\mathbf{v} = \\left[ u_0 v_0, ~~ u_1 v_1, ~~ \\ldots,~~ u_{n-1} v_{n-1}  \\right]. \\end{equation*}"
    },
    {
        "front": "dot product <br> or <br> inner product (vectors)",
        "back": "Given \\(n\\)-vectors \\(\\mathbf{u}\\) and \\(\\mathbf{v}\\), the <I>dot product</I> or <I>inner product</I> is denoted \\(\\mathbf{u} \\cdot \\mathbf{v}\\) or \\(\\mathbf{u}^T \\mathbf{v}\\) and is the <B>scalar value</B> given by multiplying corresponding components and summing them up: \\begin{equation*} \\mathbf{u} \\cdot \\mathbf{v} = \\sum_{i=0}^{n-1} u_i v_i. \\end{equation*}"
    },
    {
        "front": "norm squared",
        "back": "For a mathematical object \\(\\mathbf{u}\\) with an inner product operator \\(\\langle , \\rangle\\), the norm squared is denoted by \\(\\| \\mathbf{u} \\|^2\\) and defined as \\begin{equation*}   \\| \\mathbf{u} \\|^2 = \\langle \\mathbf{u}, \\mathbf{u} \\rangle . \\end{equation*} "
    },
    {
        "front": "norm",
        "back": "For a mathematical object \\(\\mathbf{u}\\) with an inner product operator \\(\\langle ~,~ \\rangle\\), the norm is denoted by \\(\\| \\mathbf{u} \\|\\) and defined as \\begin{equation*} \\left \\Vert \\mathbf{u} \\right \\Vert = \\sqrt{\\langle \\mathbf{u}, \\mathbf{u} \\rangle }. \\end{equation*}"
    },
    {
        "front": "unit vector",
        "back": "A vector \\(\\mathbf{v}\\) is a <I>unit vector</I> if \\(\\| \\mathbf{v} \\| =1.\\)"
    },
    {
        "front": "distance between vectors",
        "back": "The <I>distance</I> between two \\(n\\)-vectors \\(\\mathbf{a}\\) and \\(\\mathbf{b}\\) is the norm of the difference between the vectors, \\begin{equation*} d\\left(\\mathbf{a}, \\mathbf{b}\\right) = \\left\\| \\mathbf{a} - \\mathbf{b} \\right\\| = \\left\\|\\mathbf{b} - \\mathbf{a} \\right\\|. \\end{equation*}"
    },
    {
        "front": "correlation (vectors) <br> or <br> cosine similarity",
        "back": "The <I>correlation</I> between \\(n\\)-vectors \\(\\mathbf{a}\\) and \\(\\mathbf{b}\\) is\n  \\begin{equation*}   r=  \\frac{{\\mathbf{a}} \\cdot \\mathbf{{b}} }{ \\Vert\\mathbf{{a}}\\Vert \\,\\Vert\\mathbf{{b}}\\Vert}. \\end{equation*} "
    },
    {
        "front": "angle between vectors",
        "back": "The angle between \\(n\\)-vectors \\(\\mathbf{a}\\) and \\(\\mathbf{b}\\) is\n  \\begin{equation*} \\theta = \\cos^{-1} \\left( \\frac{{\\mathbf{a}} \\cdot \\mathbf{{b}} }{ \\Vert\\mathbf{{a}}\\Vert \\,\\Vert\\mathbf{{b}}\\Vert}\\right). \\end{equation*}"
    },
    {
        "front": "orthogonal vectors",
        "back": "Vectors \\(\\mathbf{a}\\) and \\(\\mathbf{b}\\) are <I>orthogonal</I> if and only if\n  \\begin{equation*} \\mathbf{a} \\cdot \\mathbf{b} = 0. \\end{equation*} "
    },
    {
        "front": "orthonormal vectors",
        "back": "Vectors \\(\\mathbf{a}\\) and \\(\\mathbf{b}\\) are <I>orthonormal</I> if and only if\n  \\begin{equation*} \\mathbf{a} \\cdot \\mathbf{b} = 0 \\end{equation*} and \\begin{equation*}\\| \\mathbf{a} \\| = \\| \\mathbf{b} \\| = 1.\\end{equation*} "
    },
    {
        "front": "scalar projection",
        "back": "Given \\(n\\)-vectors \\(\\mathbf{a}\\) and \\(\\mathbf{b}\\), the <I>scalar projection</I> of \\(\\mathbf{b}\\) onto \\(\\mathbf{a}\\) has magnitude equal to the length of the vector in the direction of \\(\\mathbf{a}\\) that minimizes the error to \\(\\mathbf{b}\\). The sign is positive if that component of \\(\\mathbf{b}\\) is in the same direction as \\(\\mathbf{a}\\) and negative if not. It is given by\n  \\begin{align*} \\frac{ \\mathbf{b}  \\cdot \\mathbf{a}}{ \\| \\mathbf{a} \\|}. \\end{align*}"
    },
    {
        "front": "vector projection",
        "back": "Let \\(\\mathbf{a}\\) and \\(\\mathbf{b}\\) be \\(n\\)-dimensional vectors. Then  the <I>vector projection</I> of \\(\\mathbf{b}\\) onto \\(\\mathbf{a}\\), denoted    \\(\\operatorname{proj}_{\\mathbf{a}} \\mathbf{b}\\), is the vector in the direction of \\(\\mathbf{a}\\) that minimizes the error to \\(\\mathbf{b}\\). It is given by\n  \\begin{equation*} \\operatorname{proj}_{\\mathbf{a}} \\mathbf{b} =   \\frac{\\mathbf{b} \\cdot \\mathbf{a} } { \\left \\Vert \\mathbf{a} \\right \\Vert ^2} \\mathbf{a}. \\end{equation*} "
    }
]